Finding Aid for Janet Blanchard Papers 1987-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Janet Blanchard Papers 1987-1990
Blanchard, Janet
3.5 linear ft.
Career state government worker, later wife of Michigan governor James J. Blanchard. Files detailing her career in state government and her later duties as wife of Michigan governor James J. Blanchard, 1989-1990. The collection includes extensive documentation of the Governor's Task Force on Telecommunications (1990) on which she served.
028 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
These files were received as part of the James J. Blanchard gubernatorial papers accession. Donor no. 7893.
The collection is open for research.
Janet Fox Blanchard was a native of Williamston, Michigan. She attended Michigan State University in the mid-1970s and later took evening classes in Western Michigan University's satellite program in Lansing. She graduated with a bachelor of arts degree in 1988. Until her marriage to James Blanchard in September 1989, Janet Blanchard was a career civil servant working in various state departments, serving at the time of her marriage as executive assistant of the Cabinet Council on Human Investment (beginning in 1987).
The collection is divided into three series. In addition to a few folders of biographical information, there is a small series of correspondence and other materials pertaining to her education and career prior to her marriage to Governor James J. Blanchard. The third series of papers relates to Janet Blanchard's role as First Lady of Michigan. This later series is comprised of general information, including correspondence; organizational activities files, with extensive documentation pertaining to the Governor's Task Force on Telecommunications in 1990; and events files containing speeches, drafts of talks, and related correspondence detailing her attendance and participation at various public functions.
Subjects:
Blanchard, Janet.; Blanchard, James J., 1942-; Governors' spouses--Michigan.; Michigan. Governor (1983-1991: Blanchard); Michigan. Governor's Telecommunication Task Force.; Women--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Blanchard, Janet.; Michigan Information Technology Network, Inc.; Children's Trust Fund for the Prevention of Child Abuse.; Schools--Michigan
Genre/Form:
Videotapes.; Photographs.
- Biographical/Personal
  - Vita (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1989, 2 folders; mainly photocopies (Box 1)
  - Wedding related correspondence (Box 1)
  - Honeymoon photographs and Christmas cards (Box 1)
  - Letter from Yousuf Karsh, 1994 (Box 1)
- Janet Fox Papers
  - Educational records (Box 1)
  - Employment history (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Cabinet Council on Human Investment, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Janet Fox/James Blanchard engagement, 1989 (Box 1)
- First Lady files
  - Miscellaneous
    - Photographs (Box 1)
    - Interviews, published material (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1990, 15 folders (Box 1)
    - Volunteerism, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Organizational Activities
    - Child care initiatives (include Governor's Task Force on Child Care), 1989-1990 (Box 2)
    - Children's Trust Fund papers and videotapes, 1989-1990, 6 folders and 2 VHS videotapes (Box 2)
    - Governor's Task Force on Telecommunications
      - Budget evaluations, agendas, minutes (Box 2)
      - Correspondence and clippings (Box 2)
      - Current infrastructure assessment, 1990, 7 folders (Box 2)
      - Deliverables draft text, 1990, 8 folders (Box 2)
      - EDS and task force recommendations, 1990 (Box 2)
      - Executive order and task force vision statements (Box 2)
      - Final report-draft text (Box 2)
      - Implementation strategies-draft report, 1990 (Box 2)
      - Michigan Information Technology Network papers and videotape, 1 folder and VHS videotape (Box 2)
      - Objectives and recommendations (Box 2)
      - Potential implementation strategies (Box 2)
      - Recommended strategies-draft report, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Michigan 4-H Foundation, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - Speeches/public appearances
    - Schedules (Box 3)
    - Event files, September 1989-July 1990 (Box 3)
    - Event files, July 1990-November 1990 (Box 4)